so we have observed that when the cash
that we use as the l2 cache is used
alone it has a higher hit rate let's
look back at our example here where we
see dat a hundred twenty-eight kilobyte
cache when used alone would have a
relatively high hit rate but when we use
it after the level one cache has already
been accessed it only gets a 75% hit
rate so it looks like the l2 cache has a
lower hit rate than the l1 cache which
can be misleading so this particular
type of hit rate we call local hit rate
for this cache a local hit rate is a hit
rate that the cache actually observes of
all the accesses to that cache this many
our hits but note that all the accesses
to a level 2 level 3 etc cache are not
all the accesses that the processor
makes those accesses that have a lot of
locality get to be l1 hit and never
reach these caches so somehow their
local hit rate is lower because they
never see the easy accesses if such a
cache was alone it would see this which
we call a global hit rate essentially if
we care only about how many accesses
that the processor make go beyond a
level 2 cache then we would really be
seeing this but note that this hit rate
really includes the hit rate of the
level 1 cache and what are the actual
hits in the level 2 cache so when we
talk about the cache size and how bigger
caches behave better and so on as far as
hit rate is concerned usually we think
about the global hit rate because the
local hit rate heavily depends on what
do you have as the level 1 cache if it's
a level 3 cache then it's local hit rate
would depend on what is the level 1 hit
rate what is the level 2 hit rate and
only then we even get to access the
level 3 cache
it's global hit rate is going to be
similar to a hit rate of that type of a
cache if it was used alone